In this American English pronunciation video, we're going to learn how to pronounce the schwa vowel sound.
在这段美式英语发音视频中，我们将学习如何发音中元音音素。
This vowel is always unstressed.
这个元音总是非重读的。
The mouth position is a lot like the UH as in BUTTER vowel, but that vowel can be, and usually is, stressed.
嘴巴的位置很像 BUTTER 中的 UH 元音，但那个元音可以是重读的，通常也是重读的。
But just like that vowel, everything in your lips, jaw, and neck should be relaxed for this sound.
但就像那个元音一样，你的嘴唇、下巴和脖子的一切都应该放松来发出这个音。
Just slightly drop your jaw to make this sound.
只需稍微放下下巴来发出这个音。
The trick is to keep everything else relaxed.
诀窍是保持其他一切放松。
Let's look at the vowel up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个元音。
It's possible to make this sound on its own with just the slightest jaw drop, but in actual words, you will likely see a bit more jaw drop, like here on the word SOFA.
可以仅通过轻微的下巴下垂来单独发出这个音，但在实际单词中，你可能会看到下巴下垂得更多，比如在单词 SOFA 中。
Lips relaxed, cheeks relaxed, tongue forward and relaxed.
嘴唇放松，脸颊放松，舌头向前并放松。
As I said, this vowel can only be in an unstressed syllable.
正如我所说，这个元音只能出现在非重读音节中。
All other vowel and diphthong sounds can either be stressed or unstressed.
所有其他元音和双元音音素可以是重读或非重读的。
So the schwa will always be really fast and low in pitch.
所以中元音总是非常快且音调低。
Uh, uh.
呃，呃。
Sofa, uh.
沙发，呃。
Ability, uh.
能力，呃。
The schwa goes with the syllabic consonants L, M, N, and R.
中元音与音节辅音 L、M、N 和 R 搭配。
That means when you have a syllable with a schwa, followed by one of these consonants, you don't need to make the schwa.
这意味着当你有一个中元音音节，后面跟着这些辅音之一时，你不需要发出中元音。
It gets absorbed by the next sound.
它被下一个音吸收。
For example, the word father, ther, ther.
例如，单词 father，ther，ther。
Just go from the TH sound right into the R sound without trying to make a separate schwa.
只需从 TH 音直接进入 R 音，而不必尝试发出单独的中元音。
Father, ther.
父亲，ther。
The schwa, always unstressed.
中元音，总是非重读的。
Uh.
呃。
Sofa.
沙发。
Uh, uh.
呃，呃。
Ability, uh.
能力，呃。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Allow, uh.
允许，呃。
Allow.
允许。
Extra, uh.
额外，呃。
Extra.
额外。
Data, uh.
数据，呃。
Data.
数据。
Again, uh.
再一次，呃。
Again.
再一次。
Visa, uh.
签证，呃。
Visa.
签证。
About, uh.
关于，呃。
About.
关于。